you're gonna say something about it if
most recollected us then properly
involves seeing yourself in feeling
rather than the feeling in you right
right right yeah well it's it's it's the
same principle as as it always is the
correctness of the body usually when a
person starts doing the like mindfulness
for the body it's sort of you know I'm
attending to my body and I am I'm
mindful of the body of bringing the mat
myself back to the body so you put
yourself first if want to view first
your attentions first and then it finds
the body because you were told you
should do so but the more you do it if
you do it correctly you start to
understand that actually it's not about
you attending to the body but it's
certainly that the body is there so that
you can attend it and it's that
knowledge of what's already there so you
ordered in a way start seeing as
yourself within the container of the
body including your own thoughts your
own feelings within the necessary basis
of the body not other way around as in
body exists only when you attend to it
so excited so the amount of the body you
kind of undermining that sense of self
yeah you are you are you're fixing the
perverted order yeah of me first body
second but so and by fixing the order
you directly exactly undermining that
that primacy that you have completely
assumed promise that promise I assume
first I'm not going to view and then
this or that depending on what I choose
but the knowledge of of the wreck
recollecting this is the knowledge yes
the necessary base so the body then
induce regardless of what you attend to
so is discerning that and if you descend
that you see that you have within it and
you cannot be outside of it it's in
consumed when you think outside of the
body that's within the base of the body
and you
that provides you with his experience
and then the same comes down to the
feeling as well see when you remindful
of the feeling it's immediately because
it sort of appears and one of its
carries comes a distant opal or more
emote or less perceivable so to speak
which means kind of assuming it's it's
not inside yeah inside of this body or
inside the inside it's in silent got a
feeling in my head so I am that thing
that has feelings yes but if you learn
how to discern it as something that
endures regardless of whether you attend
to it or not yeah you get to see the
dead feeling induced and you are the one
who goes left and right up to town in
terms of your thinking or actions or
choices so you start seeing yourself
fully enclosed within the feeling yeah
so that's another layer of that primacy
being removed so same principle same
principle yet if you're just taking it
on a different phenomenon and then again
the same like mind the mood you're in
you would be regarding it as I adhere
and mood comes and goes but I remain
here and it's just I have different
moods and it's other way around yeah
mood is here and you're second to it but
because you always seem to be the same
to you to yourself you assume that
that's what stays unchanged but doesn't
matter how unchanged it stays it's
always dependent upon the present
enduring mood yeah it's always dependent
upon present enduring feeling that's
where the good house or if the pleasant
feeling if the feeling is yours when
this this man said yeah feeling is mine
I'm like basically I'm the owner of my
feelings that's that's where my self is
and the Buddha said well which feeling
is in them because they three dumped so
you can't have them all three present so
which means you have no say in their
arising and enduring yet here you are
regarding a secured the first you are in
charge you precede them you rule over
them so same way the moods that our
moods come and go another donation would
come and go would be if you can step
outside of yourself and see would come
and going you always have a mood
enduring Moody's always there is always one note
Moody's always there is always one note
he's always one mood there's always one
feeling it was one bother it was one
body was always one image he's always
one image exactly within which you are
in yeah yeah if you start seeing
yourself second doesn't matter how much
you feel like you're the one that
doesn't I'm changing phenomenon doesn't
matter if you still the discern the mood
that's presently enduring and then see
yourself within it not other way around
and that's already you're kind of
aligning things right there
so now the mood in dues you don't have
to think about it you can then do other
things in the mood is still there and
you don't have to keep attending to it
either yeah you can just everyone then
look back and then we're still there
yeah well what mood is still there so
the mood is there someone has to be
there good elated depressed something
has to be there in a state of mind so
whether the mood has changed it still
dude yeah anything like on you don't you
do and you don't need to or must observe
how the mood changes it's completely
relevant yes what's relevant is the mood
is there in your second to it yes so sir
might mindfulness with calling you
calling it recollected person that seems
to be a really good way of naming it
because it's about basically it's about
recognizing something that's enjoying
yeah and then recollecting it every now
and then because they're not you know it
does the thing in order for you to in
order to recognize that it's enduring
yeah you have to yet there has to be
that kind of not staring at it yeah yeah
yeah if you're staring at something well
if you're staring at something you put
yourself first or too many one day yeah
and then the endurance of that thing
it's not its second it's dependent on
your attention yeah yeah that's right
yeah and and that's why mindfulness
right I can't I mean I use this because
people can relate to it but I don't like
it because it's more associated with
that attentiveness yes I'm attending to
this fully I am mindful of this yeah so
you can only know the thing is enduring
if you're staring at it yeah where is
that such thing it's the opposite
yeah the opposition so we what you attend you
the opposition so we what you attend you
can only attend because the thing you
order didn't do is that before you
attend it and you know it which is why
you choose to attend it but if you keep
prioritizing your attention of the body
the body the body and other knowledge
the dead body is there because if I ask
you do still have arms and you don't
know you wait wait let me check you will
know the answer so that's what you want
to learn how to discern that knowledge
that you already know of what's already
there did sort of precedes at least
structurally precedes as in it comes
first within which you can attend and
choose and so on and that's how it stop
assuming outside of yourself that's how
you stop maintaining that the whole
notion of active art as well because
footing the second office as first
because it was meant to be first but you
were putting there which is first a
second because you put yourself first
yeah well your point of view or your
attention or your choice and so on so if
there is a present feeling enduring
doesn't matter how distant how small how
pleasant harm present might feel you
regard that as this is the basis any
movement I make in regard to it is
within that basis cannot step outside
cannot spillover cannot become something
else even your different knowledge of it
everything that's the thing that
occurred to me your knowledge of
something
usually one thinks of your knowledge of
some I know that's all I understand this
it's something that I have I is
something in me yeah yeah again you won
these this unchanging vector there where
it's actually properly understanding
these phenomena is about laying then
come first
doctors are something like men letting
them reveal themselves as what as they
are so the knowledge is more in them
than in me the knowledge is just that
thing yeah yeah partially the only the
only thing is you need to know what to
look for that yet the instruction right
has external appearance of another needs
to come first yeah I mean in in rare
cases somebody can figure out themselves
and that's when they become either son
or something of a checkerboard yeah but
generally people need need need pointers
but then yes pointers not to like invent
or create this knowledge point is to
discern what's then here it is there now
you just know what to look for and then
you get to see it because it's they're
not in news and not your creation that's
all the the characteristics of the
nature of things all these things we
talk about in terms of the body and use
that beforehand and throughout like you
cannot as I said you cannot sort of
disturb that order you can pretend you
did yes and you can believe you did yeah
but your belief makes no difference to
the factual order of things
yeah but is first what is your container
what is the full enclosure you cannot
step outside it and everything even the
notion of outside is the on the basis of
that container of the body how can you
know the outside with other senses and
sense the completely body which means
the notion of outside real as such is
actually fully inside of the body so to
speak yeah because it's inconceivable
without it and that's the great
collections of the body in a nutshell or
just a principle of that recollection
Asante in a nutshell
but it's the feelings the moods that's
the principle you want to see the Europe
within it not all the way around and
that's how you automatically approve the
ownership because usually people try to
understand the not-self by saying to
themselves that this is not self look
it's constantly changing thus it cannot
be mine there is no dust in a you know
you know in a direct insight there is no
delay yeah there is no oh this and then
because of that this is the result
yeah no it's with this this is so with
the body first my sense of self is not
mine without the body first my set yourself
without the body first my set yourself
is mine with ignorance earth aging that
lost whatever craving fighting and
everything else that comes with it
mm-hmm by putting yourself first
everything about revolves around a yeah
that's it yeah but you can't decide I'll
put myself second because you'll be
doing it from the center of I so you can
then discern what the Buddha said which
is the order as it is regardless of your
ignorance your belief means like Oh even
if I wish that this is first and body
secondly even then which is based on the
body being first thoroughly
understanding that all these wishes
believes assumptions even orleans cannot
remain because they can only remain
because you you're not looking at them
yeah they're only they're based on your
assumption yeah and that's that's what means
yeah and that's that's what means
mindfulness developed the extent
necessary yeah extent necessary for for
being unable to assume the wrong border
anymore being unable to assume the wrong
goal that means being unable to take up
the ownership of your own senses you
don't aggregate you don't sense yourself
and also like you can be practicing like
regardless or the the state of mind you
are in so now if you're very clear
tenifer very muddled doesn't matter is
it the body's there first
not at the expense of how you feel you
just want to put it in the right order
oh I couldn't feel anything if the body
is not there life
yeah couldn't be in this smoothie the
body's not there alive and then allow
that body there being alive to enduring
that peripheral so the feeling of the
mood is always within the body
yeah but in itself they can serve for
the same principle mindfulness which
means if you're mindful of your feelings
basically you're mindful of your body
automatically if you're mindful of your
mind you're mindful of your body if
you're mindful of the images and
phenomena you might love your body but
obviously phenomena are much more subtle
to discern this principle like cuz he
thoughts are in me it's just always like
the thoughts in my head so today I have
thoughts it would be hard to see
thoughts as the first and now within the
enduring thought we have a sense of my
point of view and everything else it
with the Indian during thought but if
you start doing that on the level of the
body and maintain it yeah thoughts will
have to be included eventually yeah so
really it isn't so much the the body or
the feeling or the moon that's the
important thing it is with this this is
not Oh with this this will be or with
this every like when this has arisen
then this will come to be and because of
that I cannot have it all that is
delayed all that secondary and all
that's not a direct insight of the
petite some part
it's just seeing that the ground affects
any discerning the ground yeah Chrissy
you're not this sermon your discernment
it's already it cannot be also except
within that ground
so mindfulness is not so much about you
must think you know focus on the body
you're going to keep staying with the
body it's more it's just recognizing
anything really
that's enduring yeah that's a good solid
point that's I mean it's completely the
opposite direction of what you're
attending it and yeah
anything that's in anyone we can attend
to it's already secondary to your senses
yes let alone secondary to a point of
view to your choice to your own
attention yet the problem is in the
senses in the point of view in your
wrong attention are you on its own
Monica and you cannot possibly see that
because you're focusing you're focusing
on this focusing on that which means
that which precedes that focusing that
which focusing is result ups completely
invisible yeah so recollection is needs
to start by discerning what is the basis
to it all
where do you focus or not doesn't matter
this has to be an enduring basis
inseparable from as the widow would say
inconceivable apart from and you already
know that it's just we are so dependent
on our own choices attentions and
focusing high sense of control did you
even turn your downloa meditation
practice into that control and then you
hope somehow results will kind of
magically pop out of it but as I said if
I were to ask you you still have legs
are your arms still attached attached to
your body yes yes we did Amy didn't say
that so you all didn't know it if you
genuinely don't know it if you genuinely
need to agree would be level what we you
would have to then look and check and
find out and gather information the
defender you can instantaneous the
answer means the knowledge is order
today you're just not seeing it in the
right light so to speak you're not
seeing its relevance rather is being huh
that knowledge did I don't need to that
I cannot attempt to actually yeah his is
there which is the reason I can attend
in choose to attend this different parts
of my body and so on
for whatever reasons
I might do their belief in a meditation
technique or whatever but the point is I
need to have the body first and it's
typing into that without needing to
stare at it look at it make it into four
object to refocus because because you
won't be that you can't focus on
so you can't focus on it but you can
know it it's like a practical rule of
thumb you're focusing on it it's not it
yeah if you know you're focusing you're
focused on whatever whatever right in
front of me I focus on that but what
else do I know
one of folks on that that's how it
started out with the proper mindfulness
by discerning what children you know
what is it that makes it possible for me
yeah what is the necessary base for me
so I'm choosing to focus I don't know on
that Cup I'm focusing on I'm examining
I'm looking at him thinking about it I'm
even thinking about it significance and
use and maybe I really like the cup
maybe I dislike it whatever all those
movements of the mind that's already all
second and within when I say second I
mean he comes after I just mean it
doesn't it requires all right yeah it's
it's second you know you know in a
structural memory like a second floor is
second to the first floor but they're
both simultaneously there so you might
be focusing in a cup for whatever reason
you're focusing on the comfort or
whatever you choose to focus usually
things that well they determine the
currently enduring feeling as well
that's what your attention would be on
the base of how you feel so while that's
enduring you check is the body still
there he's something felt still there
he's the mood still there obviously
thoughts are still there
doesn't matter what thoughts what
focusing phenomena you know what matters
is it's a at first it's already there
it's enduring which is one cannot focus
on this miss Lister's and that's how you
you you also get understand and
discovered like your own intentions
behind your focus in your actions your
desire your hopes your efforts personal
yeah because they're always then
attention is always rooted in the
enduring feeling in how you feel good
and that has to be there for throughout
of your endeavors because if that thing
changes your inner will stop because
motivation is gone you wouldn't be doing
this well I guess
I guess it's quite possible for people
to think that a feeling is not necessary
but it's actually it's just like yeah
because again they still see themselves
at first we have been feeling is
circumstantial said it's missing this
thing that sometimes I am assailed by
feel yes most the time I'm not really
that's when the wrong order has been so
perverted and like almost a click like
solidified yeah in that in that in the
wrong order
yeah and now that no this is how it is I
don't need this intended but so then you
need to start overriding that because
again all you need to ask yourself is
well are you liable to suffer can you
remain truly truly indifferent to
whatever feeling comes your way and the
only answer the only way you can say
that yes is if your another hand which
means you would have undone the order
and then you would know what I'm talking
about but if you thought oh I don't need
like feelings comes and gone locks are
not affected by that no you believe you
are not affected by them now cuz nothing
bothers you now but you're still
affected by the pleasure which means you
will be affected by the bother by the
loss of pleasure by not enough pleasure
all these things as the were described
as the as the best for suffering but so
you realize ok so the knowledge is there
already I'm just choosing to ignore it
because it makes me feel unpleasant the
knowledge that I am liable to feeling
which means feelings precede me feelings
are more fundamental than than you than
me and my ownership of them and they
come and go on their own in a sense of I
depend on their coming and going yet I
have no control over it not well they
come and go in order to dismiss them yes
because people are everything shall pass
no you want that's a good white thing I
depend I depend on them but I can't
control yeah doesn't matter they're
coming and going yeah where do they're
coming whether you're going you're
affected by that by coming and going so
when people say oh it's a permanent
impermanent look pass they do it just to
like just oh ok to realize about it yeah
just to manage it exactly but not that
cannot uproot it yeah because you stay
well yeah you are liable to them whether
you believe in it or not but you live
else otherwise it's that is the de facto
state of things they come first so
unless and it seemed like the world
although simulates in terms sensuality
and something it relates to this IO you
climb the tree in pursuit of pleasures
and so on to eat mangoes and whatnot and
you know that tree will have to come
down there somebody will cut it or go
and if you don't come down you will be
killed by falling from a great height
so saying you are the one who goes into
the domain of feelings the body through
your ownership assumption for as the
Buddha said like borrowing ordering
jewellery borrowing gold and then
becoming dependent on that pleasure and
mirror age until you get from it but you
did done you know you took it you
borrowed it you did not create it yeah
you are not it's it's it's the day I
become what you know that the owner will
come yeah you just choose to believe
that like you deal with it even affected
by how they were that happens and
usually if you may tell me that in that
keep that view little bit too late to
that embarrass the longer you keep that
view the heart it would be to endure him
that more if then can you cry the
customs yeah she's like oh so where is
the problem now so I start focusing our
focus on my body and maybe like you
become familiar with it that's all it
did result problem maybe the problem is
that you are liable to what happens to
the body to you cannot remain
emotionally indifferent what happens to
feelings you cannot remain emotionally
indifferent mood you cannot remain
emotionally indifferent why is that
because you were still again by assuming
that you come first there in them second
and you make yourself liable to them
yeah by seeing it correctly you
literally pull us up out of it you're
not anymore
engaging with on and that's really you
abandon the modest the main you can't
chase smarter way you're the one in his
property and said what is the Buddha
said what is the property of matter that
you take because of which you know
everything can ascend you Marla can
control it the eye decides the nose that
smells all the senses and that's okay so
it's not mine
none of that can be mine but it's all
about all this in our mind this is our
minds about seeing it coming first and
during first being given to you for use
and then maintaining that context
maintaining that knowledge like I can
ask you know can you focus on your feet
how how you are you feel caught holding
your feet that Cal a bit cold so you
focus in a particular aspect of your
body yeah yeah yeah would it be possible
for you to focus on your feet to tell me
whatever perceptions down there if your
bodies there's no ghost oh yeah you
completely can all that what you already
know yeah and then start to just like
I'll just focus I'll just look closely
and closer and closer and somehow see
the magical reality behind it and when
you find if you find yourself for
example can't help but focusing on this
so focusing with that you all must stop
this no you just need to see that the
body the necessary base in during why
are you focusing yeah and then you're
focusing becomes redundant you will
focus only when there is a purpose to
focus you won't focus for some projected
idealistic purpose of enlightenment
practices ya know the possibility of the
fact that I'm focusing on my left
Coldfoot right now it's just one of the
options that have been presented by this
body exactly and in the irony of it is
the more you prioritize focusing in
order for you to discover your body yeah
the further away from the body you are
yeah because your body is that knowledge
that precedes the focusing yeah but you
are so unaware of it you have no means
of discerning it the only way you can
get a sense of bodies with these body
sweeping techniques and focusing with
knees and shoulders and and belly on top
of my head and down okay keep keep doing
keep moving keep moving and then you get
a sense of body that's already like a
secondary second to the sense of body
that's a necessary basis for you to even
begin that focusing let alone but it
create another image of the body from
your focusing it's kind of Chris
reductionist just realized as you said that what its
just realized as you said that what its
reaction is in order to rebuild image
doesn't mean you focus on this and then
you focus on that you focus on that so
that you can add it all together to
create this nice for all and not in what
remains first throughout that the body
that makes all that possible first place
factually but for the person who does
that it's the sense of self-reliance
first sorry even when they rediscover
the body through their cessation war
changer that's great it's still oh I'm
in categorizing eyes this is resulted
from my effort yes so hi the finish yeah
yeah yeah
so again comes down to sense of control
you see it comes down to pursuit and
fulfillment which is the principle of
sensuality as well yes so even if you
end up doing that you're observing
senses on the basis of the senses
pursuing it getting what you want
building what you want seeing what you
want you're just meditating with your
own centrality here as the bonus so many
times said and you're literally like
focusing you know people say oh you can
but the soldier is focused on his aim
it's my fault yeah and often you hear
similar similar kind of comparisons and
then exactly and then you find a
suitable said yeah yeah it's like like a
cat focus on a hole with a mouse is
there this is me now focused focus on a
mouse cat than the fish crane on the
fish I can't remember every word which
anyone was hunting which one but soon as
I see was the hunters focusing type like
full-on focuses nothing else exists for
me I'm hundred percent focused in my aim
and the Buddha said that is meditating
with sensuality yeah but because of that
you over made it the mystery you cannot
meditate because you don't see the
background you don't see the right
context for which you need knowledge so
if your practice is right so focusing
sensation watching or any weak
narrowing you are like a jackal like cat
like an owl but I can anymore trying to
catch its prey
and people think that's that's kind of
lofty oh it's like one mindedness and
the Buddha mocktail unfortunate good
amok they says they they call them
people who meditate like that call
themselves meditators yet here they are
shoulders and head drooping and whatever
else and it's all they do is meditate
with their own sexuality you might not
be pursuing the sense object in itself
in terms of the common sense objects of
pleasure but you supersuit pursuing the
objects of your focusing yes which means
the still objects of your senses so I
guess that so it's still objects of your
sensuality but that that move away from
the grosser domain of sensuality feels
like oh this is hell this is right but
you only move away from it like
circumstantially exactly in the nature's
within a single earth the second that's
what I said doesn't matter how much you
do that type of meditation you're still
within the domain of sensuality and the
danger is of course the you enter
dangerous you can sustain that yeah you
can focus only in certain periods of
time and yeah you can push yourself
eight hours a day do a three-month
retreating in whatever IP develop views
on top of this while you do of course
you cannot remain it different you
cannot remain indifferent in the fact
that you are drilling down in the
direction of central focusing so far
away from the context that's necessary
for even you beginning to do it yeah
means the further you go the less you'll
be able to see it and so your
understanding of what the body is
screaming as in but yeah exactly far and
far removed from what actually is there
and you could still technically know it
if you were to disallow it when I
already know this
they were body yes okay maybe I develop
that knowledge without needing to focus
on it but it's gonna be harder and
harder to do because each time you
choose to double down on your focusing
technique a mate of prey or whatever
goal you want each time you end up
investing yourself more which means
you're gonna have more views on account
of it no significance to it and it'll be
harder to undo it
insane look without the object of my
meditation but when people ask for the
object to focus on slick should tell me
what to hunt yeah exactly yeah
tell me what to stare at centrally wait
wait with the census assumed first no
Yuri come on man delegate to pass the
tell me what - what - calm down tell me
what - what - what - watch and observe
but not tell me what to understand yeah
so the object of meditation should be
that which you cannot make a focusing of
justice or thinking yet so you need so
it's about understanding phenomena the
understanding with too much body and
what do you feel anything now
how do you feel Pleasant at present you
drop so did you need to stop sitting
resting your arms thinking were you
about to think you know to find out
later on that was already done you
answer immediately as soon as I finish
the sentence you ask for what you felt
yes it's already there yeah so learn how
to then see what's already there we'd
only need to stop doing everything else
in the template and find it and in doing
that
and I trying to say you're sort of it's
coming coming for becoming familiar with
something that you you can't know by
looking at it hmm
exactly you can't observe your feeling
yeah you can only feel it
- because that comes first and I'm fully
enclosed within it I it's like I can't
because at website um I can't you can
relate to it relate to it I can't know
exactly I just so allow that thing
this will reveal itself exactly in you
even when you forget about it you're
forgetting of it he's within it yes
that's where you can remember him that's
why you don't need to are more always I
must always have it present in my mind
that's impossible
yeah could your mind you are result of
it you will be done it so you can't
choose to hold this presently no it's
gonna be present for as long as it is
present by yourself in itself that's
what so to say I know this or I
understand this hmm
almost the old way would be I am doing i
comfort sure really what when you can
properly say I know this or I understand
this it's about stopping doing anything
in relation to it and I'll allow
relative stopping though but stop it
continues sorry doing continues but it
ceases to be a doing yeah yeah doing in
terms of movement through a attitude
towards it that's all within that
something like whether you choose to
focus on it or forget about it all of
that makes no difference to do it it's
within it discerning that doesn't stop
the doing but he moves the passion from
the doing it removes the wrong order but
it does remove the wrong relation to it
well knowing it stops the doings they
were dependent on the passion on the
wrong border and everything else but
doesn't stop all doing yeah yeah okay so
that's what I mean all you need to do is
maintain that right order that this
container of the current Nick felt
feeling in do is regardless of a way my
arms talk to you too fast dog slows it
down but silent yeah I still feel the
same forget about it I forget about it
we start doing about something else
yeah then I remembered it time has
passed passing of the time is within the
passing of the time is within the
duration of the feeling feeling is not
in time so you realize oh it's the same
feeling I didn't even have to think
about it I just need to know it yeah
whenever I remember it so at the end of
the day I remember it's still the same
feeling so you were basically
recollected throughout a day without
making effort to be recollected without
thinking but whenever you remember it so
to speak you remember the correct order
which means nothing that's happening
right now can approve that order cannot
change that order it's seen against the
right light and that's the whole point
so you and there again I said many times
that's what I said you can't have too
much of mindfulness you can't have too
much of the knowledge of what's already
there you can have too much of
investigation you can have too little
off I just can't think about anything
but you can't have too much of knowing
that the right principle of mindfulness
the pot is already there the feeling is
already there
all the body's already yeah but not
theoretically the body's already there
oh the feeling is already there yes so
how do you feel I feel Pleasant so
that's already there so within that
pleasure now all the intentions
everything you choose to do will be
within that which means that type of
feeling that carbon enduring for you
will be influencing everything within it
here and that's not up to you that kind
of precedes your choice that's the basis
for your choice yeah and that's also how
you stop being attached to pleasure
because you realize oh it's not up to me
you subjected to it
so the surrogate can you pursue the
pleasure unless it's for you unless it's
Camille to be felt unless you assume I'm
first as that's the feeling that's my
end goal but wait I already feel
I already feel the end goal as well oh
but I don't have it the way I wanted to
or similar which means also actually my
pursuit of pleasure is rooted in already
feeling the pain of not having it so can
I change the order of that pain by
getting no it's impossible
it's inconceivable it's its second -
this is just it's always second to that
you wouldn't be able to pursue pleasure
if you don't feel anything tell me
that's inconceivable so when do you
perceive pleasure when you want to
escape the pain and when you don't have
enough for pleasure which is painful not
having enough pleasure
hmm so you pursue pleasure when you feel
pain yet here you are believe that your
pursuit and accomplishment of pleasure
is somehow gonna kind of replace
everything and and stay with you because
you've created it but in the reason you
would even make an effort to create that
pleasure is because you were subjected
to the feeling in the first place and
that pleasure tracing it's another
feeling you're gonna be subjected to
yeah see when you get the pleasure you
can't get the pleasure no you can you
can make yourself subjected to pleasure
may be subjected to pain your foot may
find that a certain feeling arises that
you were hoping for yeah yeah or not
your mind sometimes you pursue the same
thing and oh it doesn't feel the same
anymore yeah sometimes oh why I got so
much pleasure from this I didn't expect
it yeah you're always liable to feel it
but for as long as you keep pursuing it
in a manner of I'm first and I'm getting
this you maintain the order that you are
first and you could be living completely
oblivious to the fact that you are
liable to it and that's why you suffer
now because of what you feel or how you
feel it is because you just keep trying
to well you keep maintaining that
discrepancy of the assumption that I
understand because if some you put yourself first
because if some you put yourself first
you apply the your master of things
master the body muscle feeling even
those things don't go the way you want
them you suffer because not because they
didn't go the way I want but because of
your mastery cause the discrepancy lets
felt this pain you like you wouldn't
suffer T somebody comes and cuts down
the tree and you sit back you just want
to suffer
yeah so yeah but if you're asking the
tree is not the suffering but if someone
cuts down the tree while you're trying
to keep it up there and holding it there
why do you climbed up at the top here
yeah yeah so you come down captains of
the tree still occurs but no emotional
result in you know suffering but if you
refuse to give up the mastery under this
is my tree yeah I don't care by the time
you come down I already cut it so you
have a choice you can you can remain
like indignant and and hold on to what's
what's yours but if it's truly yours
nobody could cut it nobody could have
proved it nobody could destroy it is
there really the fact here the case we
don't know so it's just your own
intoxication look like a drunk man no I
can do this I can fight yeah
hundred people and I can win and then
you slip and fall by yourself literally
so you choose to refuse to give it up
despite all the evidence that you should
oh look they're coming with the axes
death old age sickness around me and so
no no no I'll keep that all sytem he's
always gonna stay for me cuz there's no
charge yeah
that's or even things like aging death
sickness and not suffering in himself
mmm chopping with the tree doesn't
matter the only matters if you're in it that's
the only matters if you're in it that's
it those are enhancing the serving the
Buddha died when they said oh I'm sorry
put it out as well I mean of course how
can that be just the arisen not pops on
it's like it's inconceivable to briefly
that's impossible
he requires this extreme level
intoxication to grieve over death
something like indifference who was like
here isn't that indifferent to life and
different to death during the one I
delight not in life just like I said I
do like nothing death I await my time
like hireling his wage yeah yeah yeah
the tryst is like your art so it's
nothing so regardless of whether the
tree stays up for longer or not
to have a preference over whether I'm
subjected to feelings or not is is the
result of you already being subjected to
feeling them surgery you can't stop
having a preference or you can start
seeing the right context of that
preference which is that oh it's second
to the already enduring feeling which is
why I prefer this over that that's it